終末なにしてますか？忙しいですか？救ってもらっていいですか？
威廉：末日时在做什么？有没有空？可以来拯救吗？
What do you do at the end of the world? Are you busy? Will you save us?
スペシャルオーディオドラマ
威廉：特别广播剧
Special Audio Drama
「ショートショート詰め合わせ」
：《小故事合集》
"Short Story Collection"
六年八班
：六年八班
Class 6-8
ヴィレム先生
：威廉老师
Mr. Willem
出欠編
阿尔弥塔：点名篇
Attendance Part
起立！
阿尔弥塔：起立！
Rise!
礼！
阿尔弥塔：敬礼！
Bow!
おはようございます
：早上好
Good morning.
ヴィレム先生！
：威廉老师！
Mr. Willem!
おーっす
威廉：噢
Yo.
じゃあ出欠とるぞ
威廉：那开始点名了
Alright, taking attendance.
出席番号一番
威廉：学号1号
Number one.
アイセア・マイゼ・バルガリス
威廉：艾瑟雅·麦杰·瓦尔卡利斯
Ithea Myse Valgulious.
ほーい！
艾瑟雅：吼咦！
Yep!
返事は「はい」だろ、アイセア
威廉：回答要说“到”吧，艾瑟雅
You're supposed to say "Here," Ithea.
はーい、ヴィレム先生
艾瑟雅：到，威廉老师
Heeere, Mr. Willem.
たく
威廉：真是的
Good grief.
二番、アルミタ
2号，阿尔弥塔
Number two, Almita.
あい！
阿尔弥塔：矮！
Yuh!
アルミタ
威廉：阿尔弥塔
Almita.
「はい」な
威廉：要说“到”
It's "Here."
あい！
阿尔弥塔：矮！
Yuh!
「はい」だ
威廉：是“到”
Say "Here."
ふ
阿尔弥塔：呜……
Uhh...
えへー！
阿尔弥塔：嘤嘤嘤！
Waaah!
アルミタ「あい」って言っだろ！
阿尔弥塔：阿尔弥塔明明说了“到”嘛！
Almita said "yuh" already!
ええ？
威廉：诶？
Huh?
泣かせた
奈芙莲：弄哭了
You made her cry.
泣かせたすね
艾瑟雅：弄哭了呢
You made her cry, alright.
泣かせたわね
珂朵莉：弄哭了呢
You really made her cry.
って、俺のせいか！？そうだのか！？
威廉：哎，是我的错吗！？是这样吗！？
Wait, is this my fault?! Is it?!
ああ、俺が悪かったから、あ、泣くなアルミタ、あ？な？
威廉：啊——是我不对，别哭了阿尔弥塔，乖，好吗？
Okay, I'm sorry. Don't cry, Almita. Okay? There, there.
あなあ！
威廉：啊！
Ah!
ナイグラートのとろとろクッキング！
妮戈兰：妮戈兰的浓汤料理！
Nygglatho's Gooey Cooking!
絶品！イケメン男子の筋肉のハーブパイ包み
菈琪旭：极品！香草派包帅哥肉～
Exquisite! Herb-crusted Handsome Guy's Muscle Pie.
皆さんこんにちは
妮戈兰：各位观众大家好
Hello, everyone.
楽しいお料理の時間です
妮戈兰：又到了快乐的料理时间
It's time for some fun cooking.
進行は私、ちょっぴりお茶目な食いしん坊トロール
妮戈兰：主持人是我，有点调皮的贪吃食人鬼
I'm your host, the slightly mischievous and gluttonous Troll,
ナイグラートと
妮戈兰：妮戈兰，和
Nygglatho, and...
ちょっぴり影の薄い天然系助手の、ラキシュが担当します
菈琪旭：有点没存在感的天然系助手菈琪旭
I'm the slightly faint-presence, airheaded assistant, Lakhesh.
まずは、活きのいいイケメン男子のお肉を用意します！
妮戈兰：首先，让我们准备好鲜活的帅哥肉！
First, we prepare some fresh handsome guy meat!
でー、へー
威廉：嘚，嘿
Wait, hey!
出せ！
威廉：放我出去！
Let me out!
具体的には、どういうタイプのイケメンがいいんでしょう？
菈琪旭：具体来说，什么样的帅哥肉质比较好呢？
Specifically, what type of handsome guy works best?
そうですね
妮戈兰：这个嘛
Let's see.
黒髪で栗色の瞳の、十八歳くらい
妮戈兰：黑发栗色瞳孔，十八岁左右
Black hair, hazel eyes, around eighteen years old.
長期間熟成された筋肉質で脂身の少ないお人好しが最高ですね！
妮戈兰：长期熟成的肌肉发达脂肪较少的老好人是最棒的呢！
A long-aged, muscular, low-fat nice guy is the absolute best!
えっ！？食材が逃げた！？
妮戈兰：欸！？食材逃跑了！？
What?! The ingredient escaped?!
もう、スタッフ！何やってるの！
真是的，工作人员！在干什么啊！
Honestly, staff! What are you doing!
しょうがない、ちょっと捕まえてくるわね！
妮戈兰：没办法，我去把他抓回来！
I have no choice, I'll go catch him!
ナイグラートさーん！
菈琪旭：妮戈兰小姐——！
Miss Nygglatho!
あああああ！
威廉：啊啊啊啊啊！
Aaaaaah!
ゴーゴー！ティアット刑事！
旁白：Go! Go! 缇亚忒刑警！
Go! Go! Detective Tiat!
事件編
缇亚忒：案件篇
The Case File
大変だ、ティアット刑事！
可蓉：不好了，缇亚忒刑警！
It's an emergency, Detective Tiat!
どうしたんだ、コロン君？
缇亚忒：怎么了，可蓉君？
What's wrong, Collon?
テレビ局前に男が倒れていると通報が！
可蓉：电视台前有个男人倒下了！
There's a report of a man collapsed in front of the TV station!
何？出動だ、コロン君！
缇亚忒：什么？出动，可蓉君！
What? Let's go, Collon!
鑑識官のパニバル君、説明を
缇亚忒：鉴识官潘丽宝君，说明一下
Forensics officer Pannibal, give me the rundown.
ガイシャはヴィレム・クメシュ
潘丽宝：被害人是威廉·克梅修
The victim is Willem Kmetsch.
死因は右腕を噛み千切られたことによるショック性出血死です
潘丽宝：死因是右臂被咬断而导致的失血性休克死亡
Cause of death is hemorrhagic shock due to his right arm being bitten off.
噛み千切る……だと！？
缇亚忒：竟然是……咬断！？
Bitten off... you say?!
第一発見者はトロールのナイグラートさんです
第一发现者是食人鬼妮戈兰小姐
The first witness was the Troll, Miss Nygglatho.
ナイグラートです
妮戈兰：我是妮戈兰
I'm Nygglatho.
で、発見時の状況は？
缇亚忒：那么，发现时的情况是？
And what was the situation upon discovery?
深夜、スタジオを出たら人が倒れていたんです
妮戈兰：深夜从录影棚出来时，就发现有人倒在那
Late at night, when I left the studio, someone was lying there.
あまりの美味しい……じゃなくでショックで、私、びっくりしちゃった
妮戈兰：因为太美味……不对，太震惊了，我吓了一大跳
I was so delicio—I mean, shocked, I was quite startled.
深夜、人がいない時間を狙っての犯行か
缇亚忒：抓住深夜没人的时候犯的案吗
A crime committed late at night when no one was around, then.
おや、ホトケさんの指先のこれは？
缇亚忒：哎呀，死者指尖的这个是？
Oh? What's this at the victim's fingertips?
こりゃティアット刑事、文字、ですかね
可蓉：缇亚忒刑警，这个像是文字呢
Detective Tiat, these look like letters.
うーん、読めないな
可蓉：唔，读不出来啊
Hmm, I can't read it.
コロンさん、これ「占う」という漢字じゃないかしら？
妮戈兰：可蓉桑，这不是“占卜”的“占”字吗？
Miss Collon, isn't this the kanji for "Fortune-telling"?
「占う」？さっぱり分からん
可蓉：“占卜”？完全搞不懂
"Fortune-telling"? I have no idea.
ティアット刑事
潘丽宝：缇亚忒刑警
Detective Tiat.
これは血で書かれたダイイング・メッセージでは！？
潘丽宝：这难道是用血写下的死亡讯息！？
Could this be a dying message written in blood?!
そうかパニバル君、これは事故じゃない、殺人事件だ！
缇亚忒：原来如此潘丽宝君，这不是意外，是杀人事件！
I see, Pannibal! This isn't an accident, it's a murder case!
六年八班、ヴィレム先生！
：六年八班，威廉老师！
Class 6-8, Mr. Willem!
自習編
艾瑟雅：自习篇
Self-Study Part
ヴィレム先生、アルミタ怪しに出掛けて行っちゃったじゃない？
珂朵莉：威廉老师不是为了安慰阿尔弥塔出去了吗？
Didn't Mr. Willem leave to go comfort Almita?
自習とはラッキー
奈芙莲：自习真是太走运了
Lucky us, it's a self-study period.
レンはそうかも知れないけど、私は先生がいないとつまんない
莲你可能这么想，但老师不在我好无聊
You might think so, Ren, but I'm bored without him here.
ところでクトリって何月生まれっすか？
艾瑟雅：说起来珂朵莉你是几月出生的？
By the way, Chtholly, what month were you born?
突然何よアイセア
珂朵莉：突然问这个干嘛艾瑟雅
What's this about all of a sudden, Ithea?
一月だけど
珂朵莉：一月啊
In January.
一月生まれ、巻き草座のあなたの今日の運勢
艾瑟雅：一月出生，卷须草(makikuso)座的你今天的运势
Born in January, your fortune today for the Sign of the Twisted-Grass...
チャッラチャッロー！
恰拉恰啰！
Ta-da!
え、巻き何？
珂朵莉：欸，卷什么座？
Wait, sign of the what?
新しい関係性が生まれる予感
艾瑟雅：会有新的关系产生的预感
A premonition that a new relationship will be born.
気になる人がいるなら耳元で囁いて大胆にアプローチしてみよう
艾瑟雅：如果有在意的人，就用耳边低语大胆地发起攻势吧
If there's someone you like, try whispering in their ear for a bold approach.
み、耳元！？無理よそんなの！
珂朵莉：耳，耳边！？那种事做不到啦！
The... ear?! I can't do that!
ラッキーアイテムは汗だくの竹輪部
艾瑟雅：幸运物品是“大汗淋漓的竹轮麸”（日本关东美食）
Your lucky item is a sweaty Chikuwabu.
身につけると彼と大接近できるかも！
艾瑟雅：戴在身上的话也许能和他大步拉近距离哦！
Wear it and you might get much closer to him!
どうやって身につけるのよ！
珂朵莉：那种东西要怎么戴在身上啊！
How am I supposed to "wear" that?!
えー、この占いアプリ当たるんっすよ
艾瑟雅：欸——这个占卜APP很准的哦
Aw, this fortune-telling app is really accurate.
いいんっすか？チャンス逃しても
真的没关系吗？即使错过机会
Is it okay? Even if you miss your chance?
ぐぬぬぬ……
珂朵莉：咕呜呜呜……
Guhhhh...
恋愛はチャンスではない。それは意志
奈芙莲：恋爱不是机会，而是意志
Love is not a chance. It is an act of will.
おおー、いいこと言うっすね、レン！
艾瑟雅：噢——说得真好呢，莲！
Ooh, well said, Ren!
国語の教科書に書いてあった
奈芙莲：语文教科书上写着的
It was written in the literature textbook.
全てクトリ、あなたが決めること
奈芙莲：一切都取决于你，珂朵莉
It all depends on what you decide, Chtholly.
う、うん
珂朵莉：唔，唔嗯
Y-Yeah.
でも、竹輪部って……
珂朵莉：可是，竹轮麸什么的……
But a Chikuwabu...
しかし帰ってこないですね、ヴィレム先生
艾瑟雅：然而还没回来呢，威廉老师
Still, Mr. Willem isn't back yet.
レディース総長物語
潘丽宝：淑女总长物语
The Story of the Girl Gang Leader
うわあ……やばそうなの来た
威廉：哇啊……来了个不得了的家伙
Whoa... some scary-looking people are here.
あー？
缇亚忒：啊——？
Huh?
おい、こんなところに人間がいるぞ
缇亚忒：喂，这种地方竟然有个人类
Hey, there's a human in a place like this.
はっ！？ティアット！？
威廉：哈！？缇亚忒！？
Wait, Tiat?!
泣く子も黙るレディース軍団「プティング」の縄張りに入るた
菈琪旭：竟敢闯进令哭闹小孩都噤声的淑女军团“布丁”的领地
Stepping into the territory of the "Pudding" girl gang, who can make even a crying child go silent...
いい度胸じゃねえか、人間
菈琪旭：胆子不小嘛，人类
You've got guts, human.
いや、チーム名可愛いな、おい！
威廉：不是，这队名也太可爱了吧喂！
I mean, the team name is too cute!
ラキシュさんにデケえ口叩いてんじゃねえ！
可蓉：不准对菈琪旭小姐大放厥词！
Don't you talk back to Miss Lakhesh!
ワダダダダダダダダダダダダダン！
可蓉：我打打打打打打打打打打打打打！
Wadadadadadadadada!
あ、武士！
威廉：啊，武士！
Ah, a samurai!
全員集合！
潘丽宝：全体集合！
Everyone, assemble!
うす、パニバル姉さん！
：是，潘丽宝姐！
Yes, Big Sis Pannibal!
総長のおなりだ
潘丽宝：总长驾到
The leader has arrived.
うわは、あ
威廉：呜哇哈，啊
Whoa...
総？
威廉：总？
The...
長？
威廉：长？
...leader?
おい、おめえら！
奈芙莲：喂，你们几个！
Hey, you guys!
はい！
：是！
Yes!
この声は
威廉：这声音是
This voice...
あたいの名前を言ってみな
奈芙莲：大家说说我的名号
Say my name.
まさか……
威廉：难不成……
It couldn't be...
はい！
缇亚忒：是！
Yes!
刻んな肉塊は数知れず
缇亚忒：斩下的碎肉数不胜数
The pieces of meat she's carved are countless!
神をも恐れぬその豪腕
菈琪旭：连神灵都不畏的铁腕
Her iron fist fears even the gods!
歩いた後には屍の山！
可蓉：走过的路遍地尸山！
A mountain of corpses follows her path!
天空を駆ける凍える豹！
潘丽宝：疾驰天空的冰冻猎豹！
The freezing leopard that streaks across the sky!
我らが総長
我们的总长
Our leader...
ネフレン様っす！
奈芙莲大人是也！
Lady Nephren!
そう、このプティングの総長、ネフレンた、あたいのことよ
奈芙莲：没错，布丁的总长奈芙莲，就是我
That's right. The leader of Pudding, Nephren—that's me.
れ、レン！？
威廉：莲、莲！？
Ren?!
ナイグラートのとろとろクッキング！
妮戈兰：妮戈兰的浓汤烹饪！
Nygglatho's Gooey Cooking!
新鮮な成人男性のお肉が手に入りましたよ、ラキシュさん
弄到了一块新鲜的成年男性肉哦，菈琪旭桑
I've obtained some fresh adult male meat, Miss Lakhesh.
うわー、血が滴ってる！新鮮すぎ！
菈琪旭：哇——血淋淋的！太新鲜了！
Wow, it's dripping blood! So fresh!
まずは、大きなノコギリを用意……
妮戈兰：首先，准备一把大锯子……
First, prepare a large saw...
え、ダメ？
妮戈兰：诶，不行？
Wait, I can't?
放送事故？
妮戈兰：放送事故？
A broadcast accident?
ちょっと、スタッフ！
妮戈兰：等等，工作人员！
Hey, staff!
そこは怯まないでプロ根性を見せなさいよ！
妮戈兰：这种时候不要畏缩，拿出职业精神来啊！
Don't flinch, show some professional spirit!
倫理的に無理？
妮戈兰：伦理上无法接受？
Ethically impossible?
いいわよ、じゃあ私が直接プロデューサーと話しつけてくるから
妮戈兰：算了，那我直接去跟制作人理论
Fine, I'll go talk to the producer directly then.
ハッ！
妮戈兰：哈！
Ha!
またですか！？私が勝手に進行しちゃいますよ、ナイグラートさーん！
菈琪旭：又要这样吗！？那我要自己主持下去了哦，妮戈兰桑——！
Again?! I'm going to keep the show going on my own, Miss Nygglatho!
Sixty-eight
：68
Sixty-eight.
ういうい！
艾瑟雅：唔咿唔咿！
Ui-ui!
あなたのアイセア・マイゼ・バルガリスの68ラジオの時間っっす！
艾瑟雅：你的艾瑟雅·麦杰·瓦尔卡利斯的68号岛广播时间！
It's time for your "Ithea Myse Valgulious 68 Radio"!
早速お電話っすよ
艾瑟雅：马上进入电话环节
Let's take a call right away.
こんにちは
菈琪旭：你好
Hello.
ラジオネーム「悩める妖精」です
菈琪旭：我的广播名是“烦恼的妖精”
My radio name is "Troubled Fairy."
あの、最近なんだか友達の個性に埋もれて
菈琪旭：那个，最近总觉得被朋友们的个性掩盖了
Um, lately I feel like I'm buried by my friends' personalities.
影が薄いような気がしてて……
菈琪旭：存在感很稀薄的样子……
I feel like my presence is getting thin...
んん
艾瑟雅：嗯嗯
Mhm.
集団生活では優しい子ほど遠慮しちゃって
艾瑟雅：集体生活中越是温柔的孩子越会顾虑他人
In a group, the nicer a child is, the more they hold back.
前に出られないんっすよね
艾瑟雅：越不敢出头呢
They can't really step forward.
でも、それも大事な個性っすから
艾瑟雅：不过，那也是重要的个性哦
But that's also an important part of your personality.
気にする必要はないっす！
艾瑟雅：所以完全不需要在意！
No need to worry about it!
あと、悩める妖精ちゃんが主役になれる瞬間は
艾瑟雅：还有，烦恼的妖精酱成为主角的瞬间
Besides, the moment "Troubled Fairy" gets to be the protagonist...
次シリーズにもちゃんと用意されてるから
艾瑟雅：在下个系列中也有好好安排的
It's properly prepared in the next series too.
万事オッケーっすよ！
艾瑟雅：所以万事OK哦！
So everything's okay!
え、それ何の予言！？
菈琪旭：欸，那是什么预言！？
Wait, what kind of prophecy is that?!
ゴーゴー！ティアット刑事！
：Go! Go! 缇亚忒刑警！
Go! Go! Detective Tiat!
推理編
缇亚忒：推理篇
The Deduction
「占う」とは……一体どういう意味だろう、コロン君？
缇亚忒：“占卜”……到底是什么意思呢，可蓉君？
"Fortune-telling"... what on earth could it mean, Collon?
分かりました、ティアット刑事！
库蓉：我明白了，缇亚忒刑警！
I've got it, Detective Tiat!
犯人は、占い師ですよ！
可蓉：犯人是，占卜师！
The culprit is a fortune-teller!
催眠術で猛獣を操ってホトケさんを狙ったんです
用催眠术操纵猛兽袭击了被害者
They used hypnosis to control a beast and attack the victim!
ハァ……また君は適当なことを言って
缇亚忒：哈……你又在信口开河
Sigh... there you go again, talking nonsense.
ティアット刑事、目撃者が見つかりました
潘丽宝：缇亚忒刑警，找到了目击证人
Detective Tiat, a witness has been found.
何だって、パニバル君？
缇亚忒：什么，潘丽宝君？
What was that, Pannibal?
目撃者のネフレンさんです
潘丽宝：目击证人奈芙莲小姐
The witness is Miss Nephren.
私は見た。犯人の大きな体と桃色の髪を
奈芙莲：我看到了。犯人高大的体型和桃色的长发
I saw it. The culprit's large body and pink hair.
そして聞いた、血に塗れた口から漏れる妖艶な笑い声を
奈芙莲：也听到了，那沾满鲜血的口中漏出的妖艳笑声
And I heard it—the bewitching laughter leaking from a blood-stained mouth.
うふふん
妮戈兰：唔呼呼
Ufufun.
おっかないわね
妮戈兰：好可怕呢
How scary.
しかし、手がかりがこれだけじゃ手詰まりですよ、ティアット刑事
可蓉：可是，光凭这点线索查不下去啊，缇亚忒刑警
But with only this many clues, we're stuck, Detective Tiat.
そうか。謎はすべて解けた！
缇亚忒：这样啊。谜团全部解开了！
I see. The mystery is solved!
えええーっ！？
：诶诶诶——！？
Whaaaat?!
六年八班、ヴィレム先生！
：六年八班，威廉老师！
Class 6-8, Mr. Willem!
女子更衣室編
奈芙莲：女子更衣室篇
Girls' Locker Room Part
次は体育っすね
艾瑟雅：接下来是体育课呢
PE is next.
うわっ！クトリ、なんすかそれ
哇！珂朵莉，那是什么啊
Whoa! Chtholly, what's that?
ポッケに仕込んだ竹輪部がべちょべちょになっちゃったの
珂朵莉：塞在兜里的竹轮麸变得湿哒哒了
The Chikuwabu I put in my pocket got all soggy.
本当にやったんっすか、気持ち悪
艾瑟雅：你还真放了啊，好恶心
You actually did it? That's gross.
結局先生は戻ってこなかったし
珂朵莉：结果老师还是没回来
In the end, Mr. Willem didn't come back.
効き目ないな、竹輪部
珂朵莉：完全没效果啊，竹轮麸
The Chikuwabu didn't work at all.
まあそのうちいいことあるっすよ
艾瑟雅：嘛，总会遇到好事的啦
Well, something good will happen eventually.
もう！
真是的！
Jeez!
ねえ、日焼け止め塗ってくれる？
珂朵莉：呐，能帮我涂下防晒霜吗？
Hey, can you help me apply sunscreen?
ほいほいと
艾瑟雅：好的好的
Sure thing.
このキャップ、開かない……
艾瑟雅：这盖子，打不开……
The cap won't open...
うわあ、出た！
哇，喷出来了！
Whoa, it's out!
うわあ
珂朵莉：呜哇
Whoa!
やだ！こんなに飛んで、胸がべちょべちょ！
珂朵莉：讨厌！喷了这么多，胸口都湿透了！
No! It sprayed everywhere, my chest is all sticky!
いいんっすよ、どうせ使うんっすから
艾瑟雅：没关系啦，反正都要用的
It's fine, you were going to use it anyway.
んね
珂朵莉：呐
Hey...
ちょアイセア、胸にはそんなに塗らなくてもいい！
珂朵莉：等下艾瑟雅，胸口不需要涂那么多！
Wait, Ithea, you don't need to put that much on my chest!
体操着の隙間から胸元にも結構日差しが入るもんっすよ
艾瑟雅：阳光会从体操服的缝隙照进胸口很多的哦
Sunshine gets in through the gaps in your gym clothes, you know.
うん、やだもう……
珂朵莉：真是的，受不了了……
Yeah, but still...
はい、完了。次はあたいの番っす
艾瑟雅：好了，搞定。接下来轮到我了
Okay, done. My turn next.
もう……
珂朵莉：真是的
Jeez...
腕と背中を重点的に頼むっす
艾瑟雅：麻烦重点帮我涂下胳膊和后背
Focus on my arms and back, please.
うん、はあ、う、ほ、は、へあ！
艾瑟雅：唔嗯，哈啊，呜，呴，哈，嘿呀！
Mm... ah... ooh... ha... hyah!
ん？何今の？
珂朵莉：嗯？刚才是怎么了？
Hmm? What was that?
二の腕の裏側が……なも弱くで……
艾瑟雅：上臂的内侧……啊，那里很敏感……
The back of my upper arms... is sensitive...
ふーん。じゃあここ？
珂朵莉：哼——。那是这里吗？
Oh? Then how about here?
うわああ！マジ勘弁っす！
艾瑟雅：哇！饶了我吧！
Uwaaah! Give me a break!
良いではないか、良いではないか！
有什么关系嘛，有什么关系嘛！
It's fine, it's fine!
あっ！コラ、やめなさいって！
艾瑟雅：啊！喂，快住手！
Ah! Hey, stop it!
……うわ？
：……啊？
...Whoa?
乳はただの肉塊
奈芙莲：胸只是肉块
Breasts are just lumps of meat.
うわ？ん？
：啊？
Huh?
つまり、無用の長物
奈芙莲：也就是，无用之物
In other words, they're useless appendages.
おほ、ははは
艾瑟雅：哦，啊哈哈
Oho, hahaha.
体育始まるから
奈芙莲：体育课要开始了
PE is starting.
……肉塊？
：……肉块？
...Lumps of meat?
続・レディース総長物語
奈芙莲：续·淑女总长物语
The Story of the Girl Gang Leader, Continued
ネフレン総長
潘丽宝：奈芙莲总长
Leader Nephren.
ごしょごしょごしょごしょ
潘丽宝：（偷偷摸摸偷偷摸摸）
(Whispering...)
あん？人間
奈芙莲：嗯？人类
Hmm? A human.
ほら、総長にツラをお見せしろ！
可蓉：喂，快让总长看看你的脸！
Hey, show the leader your face!
だあ！離せコロン！
威廉：哒！放开我可蓉！
Hey! Let go, Collon!
レン、俺だ、ヴィレムだ！
威廉：奈芙莲，是我，威廉啊！
Ren, it's me! Willem!
ヴィレムだと？
奈芙莲：是威廉？
Willem, you say?
なあ、お前みたいな小さな子がこんなことやっちゃダメだ
威廉：呐，像你这么小的孩子不能做这种事
Listen, a little kid like you shouldn't be doing this.
こういうのはもっと大人なお姉様たちに任せてだな
威廉：这种事还是交给更年长的大姐姐们吧
You should leave this kind of thing to older girls.
邪かましわ、ボケ！
缇亚忒：烦死人了，白痴！
Shut up, you idiot!
ああーびゃシュ！
威廉：啊啊！bash！
Aaaah!
ああーびゃシュ！
威廉：啊啊！bash！
Aaaah!
てめえも結局、忌まわしき肉塊を好む淫獣ってわけか
奈芙莲：结果你也是，那种喜欢令人忌讳的肉块的淫兽吗
So you're just another beast who loves those detestable lumps of meat.
何？何の話？
威廉：什么？在说什么啊？
What? What are you talking about?
どうしやす、総長？
潘丽宝：该怎么处置他，总长？
What should we do, Leader?
下
奈芙莲：下
Down.
らっしゃーした！
：领命——！
Right away!
あ下！？下って……おい、どこに連れていく気だ！おい！ま、まさか……
威廉：下！？下是……喂，要把我带到哪去啊！喂！难、难道说……
Down?! What do you mean... hey, where are you taking me! Hey! Don't tell me...
ああああああああ！
啊啊啊啊啊啊啊啊！
Aaaaaaaaaah!
あたいは止まらない。全ての肉塊を滅ぼす、その時まで
奈芙莲：我不会停下。直到消灭所有肉块的那一刻
I won't stop. Not until the moment every lump of meat is destroyed.
ゴーゴー！ティアット刑事！
：Go! Go! 缇亚忒刑警！
Go! Go! Detective Tiat!
解決編
缇亚忒：解决篇
The Resolution
犯人はお前だ、ナイグラート！
缇亚忒：犯人就是你，妮戈兰！
The culprit is you, Nygglatho!
第一発見者が犯人？
可蓉：第一发现者就是凶手？
The first person on the scene is the culprit?
ベタだな
潘丽宝：太老套了吧
How cliché.
え、あら、何の証拠があって？
妮戈兰：欸，哎呀，你有什么证据吗？
Oh my, and what evidence do you have?
大きな体。桃色の髪。妖艶な声
缇亚忒：高大的身体。桃色的头发。妖艳的声音
A large body. Pink hair. A bewitching voice.
すべてあなたの特徴に合致している！
缇亚忒：所有特征都与你吻合！
They all match your characteristics!
いいがかりよ
妮戈兰：这是诬告
That's a false accusation.
なら「占う」というあのダイイング・メッセージは
妮戈兰：那死者留下的“占卜”这个死亡讯息
In that case, how do you explain...
どう説明するつもり？
妮戈兰：你打算怎么解释？
...that dying message about "Fortune-telling"?
これは「占う」の文字ではない
缇亚忒：这不是“占卜”两个字
This isn't the word for "Fortune-telling."
何！？
妮戈兰：什么！？
What?!
カタカナの「ト」と「ロ」だ！
缇亚忒：是片假名的“ト（To）”和“ロ（Ro）”！
It's the Katakana characters "To" and "Ro"!
ト……ロ……まさか……
可蓉：To……Ro……难不成……
To... Ro... could it be...
「トロール」！
：“Troll（食人鬼）”！
"Troll"!
ホトケさんは最後の力を振り絞って、犯人の正体を残そうとした
缇亚忒：死者竭尽最后的力气，想要留下犯人的真面目
The victim used the last of his strength to leave behind the culprit's identity.
種族という、絶対的な特徴な！
那就是种族这一绝对性的特征！
An absolute characteristic—her race!
かく
妮戈兰：咳咳……
Ugh...
ただ、美味しいお肉が食べたかっただけなのに……
妮戈兰：我只是，想吃点好吃的肉而已……
I just... wanted to eat some delicious meat...
ナイグラート、殺人容疑で逮捕する！
缇亚忒：妮戈兰，你涉嫌杀人罪，被逮捕了！
Nygglatho, you're under arrest for suspicion of murder!
ナイグラートさん戻ってこないな
菈琪旭：妮戈兰桑还没回来呢
Miss Nygglatho isn't coming back.
このままじゃ放送終わっちゃうよ
菈琪旭：再这样下去节目就要播完了
At this rate, the broadcast will end.
お？
菈琪旭：哦？
Oh?
番組の途中ですが、臨時ニュースをお知らせします
：节目途中插播一条临时新闻
We interrupt this program to bring you some breaking news.
世間を騒がせていた猟奇殺人犯が逮捕されました
：引起社会广泛关注的猎奇杀人犯已经落网
A bizarre serial killer who has been causing a public outcry has been arrested.
犯人ナイグラートは
：犯人妮戈兰
The culprit, Nygglatho...
生放送の料理番組で使用する食材確保のため
：被认为是为了筹备直播料理节目
...is believed to have committed the crimes...
犯行に及んだと思われます
所需的食材而作案
...to secure ingredients for a live cooking show.
本当に怖いですね
：真是太可怕了呢
How truly terrifying.
えっ！？番組打ち切り！？
菈琪旭：欸！？节目被腰斩了吗！？
What?! The program is cancelled?!
それとも降板？
菈琪旭：还是说要换主持人？
Or am I being replaced?
降板ね！
菈琪旭：换主持人了啊！
Replaced!
やったわ、私が主役！
菈琪旭：太好了，我才是主角！
Yay, I'm the star now!
それじゃあ皆さん
菈琪旭：那么各位观众
Well then, everyone...
来週からは新番組
菈琪旭：从下周起请收看新节目
Starting next week, please enjoy a new program...
ラキシュのふわふわクッキングを！
菈琪旭：菈琪旭的软绵绵料理哦！
"Lakhesh's Fluffy Cooking"!
お楽しみに！
菈琪旭：敬请期待！
Look forward to it!
六年八班、ヴィレム先生！
：六年八班，威廉老师！
Class 6-8, Mr. Willem!
放課後編
珂朵莉：放学后篇
After School Part
ああ……疲れた
威廉：啊……累死了
Man... I'm exhausted.
結局一日、アルミタのお守りで終わってしまった
威廉：结果一整天都在照顾阿尔弥塔
In the end, I spent the whole day babysitting Almita.
ヴィレム先生
珂朵莉：威廉老师
Mr. Willem.
うおっ！クトリ！？
威廉：呜哇！珂朵莉！？
Whoa! Chtholly?!
やだ先生、びっくりしすぎじゃない？
珂朵莉：真是的老师，你被吓过头了吧？
Honestly, Mr. Willem, aren't you a bit too startled?
耳元で囁くのはやめてくれ
威廉：别在我耳边低声说话啦
Please stop whispering in my ear.
ええー、そう言われるともっとやりたくなっちゃう
珂朵莉：欸——被你这么一说我更想做了
Aw, saying that just makes me want to do it more.
頼むからやめてくれ
威廉：拜托饶了我吧
Please, give me a break.
もう下校時刻だろ
威廉：已经放学了对吧
It's time to head home.
さっさと帰れ
威廉：快点回家
Hurry up and go back.
分かってる
珂朵莉：我知道
I know.
でも今日は先生ずっといなかったからさ
珂朵莉：但因为今天老师一直不在
But since you were gone all day...
帰る前にどうしても、顔が見たかったの
珂朵莉：回去之前无论如何，都想看看你的脸
...I really wanted to see your face before going home.
お……
威廉：噢……
Oh...
は？
珂朵莉：哈？
What?
照れてる？
珂朵莉：害羞了吗？
Are you blushing?
は
威廉：哈
Ha.
照れてなんかいない
威廉：才没害羞
I am not blushing.
えへ
珂朵莉：诶嘿
Ehehe.
竹輪部の効果、あったかな？
珂朵莉：是那个竹轮麸的效果吗？
I wonder if the Chikuwabu worked?
は？
威廉：哈？
Huh?
ううん！何でもなーい
珂朵莉：没什么！什么都没有——
Nothing! It's nothing.
じゃあね、先生
珂朵莉：那再见啦，老师
See ya, Mr. Willem!
ええへいてっいてっ！
威廉：诶诶痛痛！
Hey, ow ow ow!
耳はやめろと言っただろ！
威廉：不是说了别咬耳朵吗！
I told you to stop with the ears!
やめないもー！
珂朵莉：我才不听呢——！
I'm not stopping!
えへへ
珂朵莉：诶嘿嘿
Ehehe.
はー
威廉：哈——
Sigh...
たく……
威廉：真是的……
Good grief...
おしまい
：剧终
The End